Vincas Stonys

I'm a software engineer with 5 years of professional experience in complex front-end development and good knowledge of back-end development. I have a BE in Software Engineering and professional background mostly in fintech and security products.

Vilnius, Lithuania (370) 611-92588 vincas.stonys@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

ProtonMail, Lithuania— Software Engineer

APR 2019 - PRESENT

Working as part of a highly distributed team in a rapidly growing startup on privacy-oriented products used by over 20 million users.

- Leading FE development on E2E encrypted cloud storage web client ProtonDrive from scratch.
- Rewriting and improving customer support web app from AngularJS to React.
- FE development and maintenance on E2E encrypted email client and VPN dashboard.
- Conducting candidate interviews and onboarding, reviewing code and improving tech stack.

Sunday by Danske Bank, Lithuania— Software Engineer

MAR 2017 - APR 2019

Working as part of a distributed team to innovate on an old fashioned Danish mortgage application process.

- FE development on real estate search and mortgage web application.
- BE development in Golang for user events tracking microservice.
- Improving tech stack, conducting candidate interviews, reviewing code.
- Implementing a custom GoogleMaps client for React to optimise performance.
- Integrating a headless CMS "Storyblok" for content managers.
- Developing tools and making suggestions to increase productivity and save money

Tieto, Lithuania — Software Engineer

OCT 2015 - MAR 2017

Developing and maintaining internal Tieto applications in a small local team.

- FE development of office room management application from scratch.
- Full-stack development of invoice, expense and project management applications with Ext.JS, AngularJS and Grails.

MAIN SKILLS

React
Angular
JavaScript
TypeScript
Node.JS
HTML
CSS
Groovy
Grails
Golang
Java

C#

LANGUAGES

Lithuanian - Native English - C2 Spanish - B1

EDUCATION

Vilnius University, Vilnius — BE in Software Engineering

MONTH 2014 - MONTH 2018

A standard 4 year university course of Software Engineering in Vilnius University.

NKKM Computer School, Vilnius

MONTH 2008 - MONTH 2011

General computer skills. Programming in Pascal, Java, C# and Game development using XNA.

LINKS

ProtonMail — https://beta.protonmail.com/
ProtonVPN — https://protonvpn.com/
Sunday - https://sunday.dk/
Github - https://github.com/vincaslt
LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/vincas-stonys-4ab8039a/
Personal page - https://vincas.dev